Guide to the Urban League of Portland Records 1910-2014
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
- Records, 1910-2014; Subgroup 1; 11.8 cubic feet
  - Reports and Publications, 1940-2014; Series 7
    - Reports, 1945-2014; Sub-Series 3
      - "The State of Black Oregon", 1986-2014; 3 folders (Box-folder 10.16-10.18)
      - "The State of Our Children", 1997-1998 (Box-folder 10.19)
      - "The State of Race Relations in Springfield, Illinois", 1993 (Box-folder 10.20)
      - "To be Equal", 1999 (Box-folder 10.21)
  - Subject Files, 1910-2013; Series 8
    Series 8 consists of information regarding the Urban League of Portland's centers and conferences held and attended by the National Urban League and the Portland branch. A substantial amount of material in this series pertains to the Urban League of Portland's events. Materials include fund-raising information, memos, flyers, reports, and newspaper clippings. Issues the Urban League community faces along with the topics of health and housing are reflected in brochures, informational packets, legislative materials, write-ups, correspondence, and newspaper clippings. Series 8 also reflects programs/projects of the League, historical information, and community and internal surveys. Some materials encompass external programs and organizations. The bulk of the records are for the 1940s thru 1990s.
    - Awards, 1981-2000 (Box-folder 10.22)
    - Adult and Senior Services, 1969 -2009 (Box-folder 10.23)
    - Affirmative Action, 1970 -1995 (Box-folder 10.24)
    - Affirmative Action: "Pursuit of a Meritocracy", 1995-1996 (Box-folder 10.25)
    - Centers: Center for Career Development, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 10.26)
    - Centers: Center for Self Development, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 10.27)
    - Centers: Related to All, 1988 (Box-folder 10.28)
    - Centers: Whitney Young Learning Center, 1986-1999 (Box-folder 10.29)
    - Centers: Youth Service Center, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 11.1)
    - Conferences, 1910-1999; Sub-Series 1
      - Annual Conference on Dropout Prevention/At Risk Youth, 1987 (Box-folder 11.2)
      - Annual Delegate Assembly, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 11.3)
      - Black Leadership Conference, 1986 (Box-folder 11.4)
      - NAACP, 1910 (Box-folder 11.5)
      - National Urban League Conference, 1967 (Box-folder 11.6)
      - National Urban League Conference Speeches, 1967 (Box-folder 11.7)
      - National Urban League Western Regional Assembly, 1982-1999 (Box-folder 11.8)
    - Education, 1946-2001 (Box-folder 11.9)
    - Education: Ethnicity and Education, 1976 (Box-folder 11.10)
    - Education: Legislation, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 11.11)
    - Education: Relations with Colleges, 1946-1972; 2 folders (Box-folder 11.12-11.13)
    - Employment, 1952-1989 (Box-folder 11.14)
    - Events, 1961-2013; Sub-Series 2
      - 50th Anniversary, 1982-1995 (Box-folder 11.15)
      - Annual Dinner, 1971-2011 (Box-folder 11.16)
      - Career Awareness Day, 1978-1998 (Box-folder 11.17)
      - Career Fair, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 11.18)
      - CEO Transfer, 2012 (Box-folder 11.19)
      - Do The Right Thing Day, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 11.20)
      - The Earth We Share, 2001 (Box-folder 11.21)
      - Equal Opportunities Day, 1961-2013 (bulk: 1985-2013) (Box-folder 11.22)
      - Hand in Hand, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 11.23)
        9 photographs
      - Legislative Action Day, 2013 (Box-folder 11.24)
      - Related to all, 1996 (Box-folder 11.25)
      - State of Race Relations in Portland, OR, 1997 (Box-folder 11.26)
    - Freedom Bank of Finance, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 11.27)
    - Health: AIDS, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 11.28)
    - Health: Easter Seal Society, 1972 (Box-folder 11.29)
    - Health: Health Agencies, 1985 (Box-folder 11.30)
    - Health: Health Care, 1964-1979 (Box-folder 11.31)
    - Health: Sickle Cell, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 11.32)
    - Historical Information: National Urban League, 1985-1994 (Box-folder 12.1)
    - Historical Information: Portland's African American Community, 1945-1993 (Box-folder 12.2)
    - Historical Information: Urban League of Portland, undated, 1950 (Box-folder 12.3)
    - Housing, 1949-1997; 2 folders (Box-folder 12.4-12.5)
    - Issues, 1950-1996; Sub-Series 3
      - Drug Abuse, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 12.6)
      - Energy Conservation, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 12.7)
      - Environmental Justice, 1995 (Box-folder 12.8)
      - Lead Poisoning, 1996 (Box-folder 12.9)
      - Minstrel Shows, 1950-1957 (Box-folder 12.10)
      - White Privilege and Race Relations, 1962-1993 (Box-folder 12.11)
      - Women, circa 1960 (Box-folder 12.12)
    - Legislation: Bills, 1949-2003 (bulk: 1987-1989) (Box-folder 12.13)
    - Legislation: Economic Opportunities Act, 1963-1968; 2 folders (Box-folder 12.14-12.15)
    - Maps and Directions, 1966-circa 1970s (Box-folder 12.16)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. BLVD., 1987-2006 (Box-folder 12.17)
    - Metropolitan Economic Development Corporation, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 12.18)
    - Minorities and Media, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 12.19)
    - Minorities in Business, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 12.20)
    - Minorities in Business: Census, 1972 (Box-folder 12.21)
    - Minorities in Business: "Minority Potential", 1980 (Box-folder 12.22)
    - Minorities in Business: Proposals and Contracts, 1966-1977; 2 folders (Box-folder 12.23-12.24)
    - Office of Economic Opportunity, 1964-1970 (Box-folder 12.25)
    - Oregon Student Public Interest Research Group, 1978 (Box-folder 12.26)
    - Programs and Projects, 1955-1999; Sub-Series 4
      - Adolescent/Parent Treatment Program, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 12.27)
      - African American Leadership Program, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 12.28)
      - Albina District Program, 1963-1970 (Box-folder 12.29)
      - Albina Community Action Program, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 12.30)
      - Big Brother/Big Sister Programs, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 12.31)
      - Developmentally Delayed Impact Program, 1987 (Box-folder 12.32)
      - Food Share Program, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 12.33)
      - Forestry Project, 1998 (Box-folder 12.34)
      - Hispanic Outreach Program, circa 1980s-1990s (Box-folder 12.35)
      - Job Development Program, 1963-1968; 2 folders (Box-folder 12.36-12.37)
      - Labor Education Advancement Program, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 13.1)
      - Metropolitan Community Action Homeless Program, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 13.2)
      - Related to All, circa 1990s (Box-folder 13.3)
      - Summer Youth Employment Program, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 13.4)
      - Summer Youth Employment Program Secretary Anderson Visit, 1998 (Box-folder 13.5)
      - Urban Plaza Building Project, 1984 (Box-folder 13.6)
      - Urban Renewal Program, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 13.7)
      - Volunteer Services Awards Program, circa 1980s (Box-folder 13.8)
    - Properties and Maintenance, 1983-1992; 2 folders (Box-folder 13.9-13.10)
    - Religious Affiliates, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 13.11)
    - Site Visit (Portland), 1992-2002 (Box-folder 13.12)
    - Student Papers, 1936-1968 (Box-folder 13.13)
    - Surveys, undated, 1983-1994; Sub-Series 5
      - Attitudes Toward Minorities, circa 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 13.14)
      - Community Surveys, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 13.15)
      - Female Responsibility Program, 1994 (Box-folder 13.16)
      - NE Portland Residents, 1988 (Box-folder 13.17)
      - Survey of Compensation Practices for the National Urban League, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 13.18)
      - Wage Comparability Study, 1984 (Box-folder 13.19)
    - Tour of Hawaii, 1967 (Box-folder 13.20)
    - Urban League of Portland Guild, 1987-1998 (Box-folder 13.21)
- Photographs and Visual Materials, 1945-2005; Subgroup 2; 8.85 cubic feet
  Subgroup 2 consists of photographs and other visual materials, including scrapbooks, posters, and plaques documenting the programs and activities of the Urban League of Portland.
  - Photographs, 1945-2005; Series 1
    Series 1 consists of approximately 6,200 photographic prints, 900 film negatives, 358 digital photographs, 30 slides, and 30 collages. This series is only minimally arranged and described. Some of the photographs are arranged by date; others by topic; and others by format. Topics include personnel, meetings, activities and programs, and buildings. A selection of the photographs are available online in the Oregon Multicultural Archives within Oregon Digital.
    - Photographs, 1940s (Box-folder 15.1)
    - Photographs, 1945-1949 (Box-folder 15.2)
    - Photographs, 1950s (Box-folder 15.3)
    - Photographs, Audrey Selis Photography, 1950s (Box-folder 15.4)
    - Photographs, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 15.5)
    - Photographs, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 15.6)
    - Photographs, 1960s (Box-folder 15.7)
    - Photographs, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 15.8)
    - Photographs, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 16.1)
    - Photographs, 1960s and later (Box-folder 16.2)
    - Photographs, 1970s (Box-folder 16.3)
    - Photographs, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 16.4)
    - Photographs, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 16.5)
    - Photographs, 1980s (Box-folder 16.6)
    - Photographs, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 16.7)
    - Photographs, circa 1980s-2000s; 32 folders (Box-folder 16.8-18.9)
    - Children and Youth at King School, 1976; 10 matted prints (Box-folder 24.1)
      Photographs by Nancy McKurlens (sp?).
    - Oversized Prints, circa 1960s-1990s (Box-folder 24.2)
    - 50th Anniversary Dinner, 1995 (Box-folder 18.10)
    - Achievement Matters Event, 1998 (Box-folder 18.11)
    - Achievement Matters Press Conference, 1998 (Box-folder 18.12)
    - Annual Dinner, 1991-1998; 6 folders (Box-folder 18.13-18.18)
    - Annual Meetings, 1960-1998; 3 folders (Box-folder 18.19-18.21)
    - Bill Berry, 1958-1974 (Box-folder 18.22)
    - Big Hats, 1950s-1960s (Box-folder 18.23)
    - Building Remodels/Flooding, circa 1995 (Box-folder 18.24)
    - Career Connections, 1992-2004; 7 folders (Box-folder 18.25-19.4)
    - CEO Photos, circa 1982-1995 (Box-folder 19.5)
    - Do The Right Thing Day, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box-folder 19.6-19.7)
    - Do The Right Thing Day Parades, 1997-1998; 2 folders (Box-folder 19.8-19.9)
    - Equal Opportunities Day, 1962-1994 (inclusive), 1993-1994 (bulk); 4 folders (Box-folder 19.10-19.13)
    - Equal Opportunities Day Dinner, 1991-1999; 8 folders (Box-folder 19.14-19.21)
    - Graduation Ceremonies, 1998 (Box-folder 19.22)
    - Grand Opening of the Ride Connection Service, circa 1990s (Box-folder 19.23)
    - Group Photograph of Staff and Youth, 1990 (Box 23.1)
    - Halloween Party, 1989 (Box-folder 19.24)
    - History Book Photos, 1960s (Box-folder 19.25)
    - E. Shelton Hill, 1951-1973 (Box-folder 19.26)
    - Holiday Parties: Kwanzaa and Christmas, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 19.27)
    - John Holly, 1959 (Box-folder 19.28)
    - Housing, undated; 2 folders (Box-folder 19.29-19.30)
    - Malcolm X Film Benefit Event, circa 1970s (Box-folder 19.31)
    - Miss Black America Lunch and Reception for L. Dark, 1994 (Box-folder 19.32)
    - Multicultural Senior Center's 6th Anniversary, 1997 (Box-folder 19.33)
    - Multicultural Senior Center Fairs and Seniors Fishing Trip, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 19.34)
    - National Urban League Conference, 2003 (Box-folder 19.35)
    - National Urban League Leadership Meeting, 2004 (Box-folder 20.1)
    - Newsletter Photos, circa 1950s-1990s; 2 folders (Box-folder 20.2-20.3)
    - Our Children Our Destiny Display, 2004; 23 photos (Box-folder 24.3)
    - Presentation By Coretta Scott King, 1995 (Box-folder 20.4)
    - Regional National Urban League Meetings, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 20.5)
    - Senior Citizen and Youth Programs: Outings and Field Trips, 2003 (Box-folder 20.6)
    - Senior Citizen Programs, 2005 (Box-folder 20.7)
    - Summer Youth Employment Program, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 20.8)
    - Trailblazers Visit to Senior Center, 1997 (Box-folder 20.9)
    - Norval Unthank, circa 1970s (Box-folder 20.10)
    - Unidentified Conference and Staff/Visitors, circa 2005 (Box-folder 20.11)
    - Unidentified Events, 2005 (Box-folder 20.12)
    - "Urban Forest" Youth Outing to Mt. Hood, 1991 (Box-folder 20.13)
    - Urban League Computer Training Center, 1997 (Box-folder 20.14)
    - Urban League Dinners, circa 1980s (Box-folder 20.15)
    - Urban League Guild, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 20.16)
    - Urban League Picnics, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 20.17)
    - Urban League Regional Conference, 1995 (Box-folder 20.18)
    - Urban League Staff, 1945-1997; 2 folders (Box-folder 20.19-20.20)
    - Various Events and Activities, circa 1990s; 11 folders (Box-folder 20.21-21.4)
    - Various Events and Urban League Staff, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 21.5)
    - Whitney Young Learning Center, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 21.6)
    - Yearbook Information, circa 1990s (Box-folder 22.1)
    - Young Professionals Event, 2004 (Box-folder 22.2)
    - Youth Program: Basketball Game, 2004 (Box-folder 22.3)
    - Youth Program: Outing to Willamette University, 2004 (Box-folder 22.4)
    - Youth Program: NULITES Outing to the Zoo, 2004 (Box-folder 22.5)
    - Youth Program: Oakley Green Middle School Outreach, 2004 (Box-folder 22.6)
      Digital photographs of this program are available for viewing in the Reading Room.
    - Type: Slides for Anniversary Presentation, circa 1950s-1990s; 142 slides (Box-folder 22.7)
    - Type: Negatives, undated; 2 (Box-folder 22.8)
    - Type: Color Slides, circa 1970s; 14 slides (Box-folder 22.9)
    - Type: Images with Velcro, 2000-2001; 10 images (Box-folder 22.10)
    - Type: Photo Collages, circa 1990s; 3 folders (Box-folder 23.2-23.4)
      Includes 30 collages of photographic prints.
    - Digital Photographs, 2004; Sub-Series 1; 358 files; 650 MBytes
      These digital photographs are available for viewing in the Reading Room.
      - Urban League Dinner, 2004; 001; 251 files; 601 Mbytes
        These images of individuals attending the annual dinner include Harold C. Williams and the following individuals from Oregon State University: President Ed Ray, Phyllis Lee, and Teryl Ross.
      - Youth Program, 2004; 002-004; 83 files; 48 Mbytes
        These images document outreach activities at the Oakley Green Middle School. Photographic prints and film negatives of these images are available in box-folder 22.6.
      - Melon Fest, 2004; 005; 24 files; 1.4 Mbytes
  - Posters, 1997-1999; Series 2; 4 folders
    Series 2 consists of 5 laminated posters and newspaper headlines, 50 "Gifts of the Elders" informational sheets, 4 unlamenated posters, and 4 stationary mockups. Some of the items are undated.
    - (Box-folder 23.5-23.8)
  - Scrapbooks and Photograph Albums, 1991-1996; Series 3; 900 photographs
    Series 3 consists of both bound and loose-leaf scrapbooks and photograph albums that include about 900 photographs. In addition to photographs, the scrapbooks include newsletters, collages of photographs, and memorabilia. Descriptions are included for some of the photographs. Urban League of Portland personnel, renovations, and events are reflected in these scrapbooks.
    - Event Photograph Album, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 25.1)
    - Untitled Photo Album (Box-folder 25.2)
    - Portland Urban League Guild, 1991-1992 (Box-item 25.3)
    - Untitled Photo Album (Box-item 25.4)
    - Employees Photo Album (Box-folder 26.1)
    - WYLC Photo Album (Box-folder 26.2)
    - Urban Plaza Rehabilitation/Alteration Photo Album (Box-item 26.3-26.4)
    - The Urban League of Portland E. Shelton Hill Achievers Corps Photo Album, 1997-1998 (Box-item 26.5)
    - Urban League of Portland Annual Dinner Photo Album, 1996 (Box-item 27.1)
    - Kwanza Event Photo Album (Box-item 27.2)
    - Untitled Photo Album (Box-folder 27.3)
    - Urban League of Portland 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, 1995 (Box-folder 27.4)
  - Plaques, 1984-1990; Series 4
    Series 4 consists of 4 items including 3 Certificates of Appreciation awarded to the Urban League of Portland by the African American Festival, One Church One Child, and the Bureau of the Census. This series also includes a plaque dedicated to the Urban Plaza by the Urban League of Portland.
    - African American Festival certificate of appreciation, 1990 (Box-item 28.1)
    - One Church, One Child certificate of appreciation, 1990 (Box-item 28.2)
    - Census '90 certificate of appreciation, 1990 (Box-item 28.3)
    - Urban Plaza dedication plaque, 1984 (Box-item 28.4)
- Audio and Video Materials, 1962-2003; Subgroup 3; 125 video and 30 audio recordings
  Subgroup 3 consists of video and sound recordings produced by the National Urban League and the Urban League of Portland as well as outside producers that document the Urban League. Topics include conferences, events, promos, service centers, interviews, and annual dinners. Running times for video and audio recordings are provided with descriptions of the items.
  - Video, 1981-2003; Series 1
    Series 1 consists of 125 video recordings produced by the National Urban League, the Urban League of Portland, other Urban League Affiliates, and outside producers. Topics include conferences, special events such as the annual Urban League Dinner and the Equal Opportuniy Day Dinner, interviews, family and race relations, youth employment, and schools. The series includes duplicate DVDs, made in about 2010 by the University Archives. Portions of several of the video recordings are available online. Links are provided from the individual descriptions to the streaming video. The bulk of the videos are VHS format; U-matic, Betacam and DVDs are also included.
    - National Urban League, 1981-2001; Sub-Series 1
      - Kellogg's National Urban League Advertisement: "Rightfield", undated (Box-item 29.1)
        VHS, Advertisement for Kellog's cereal with the National Urban League's summer baseball footage. (0:01:00)
      - Mission Statement, 1997 (Box-item 29.2)
        VHS, Discusses the reasons for changing the mission statement to "Our Children = Our Future." (0:14:00)
      - National Urban League and the Congress of National Black Churches, undated (Box-item 29.3)
        VHS, Over 2,000 youth across America are inducted into the Thurgood Marshall Achievers Society, Metropolitan Baptist Church, Washington, DC. (0:28:00)
      - National Urban League President, John E. Jacob Interview, 1981 (Box-item 29.4)
        VHS, Interview of newly elected NUL President, John E Jacob, by Coy Eklund. December 17, 1981 (0:30:30)
      - Oseola McCarty, 1995 (Box-item 29.5)
        VHS, Oseola McCarty gives her own savings to help young Urban League students. November 14, 1995 (0:10:00)
      - State of Black America Press Conference, 1994 (Box-item 29.6)
        VHS, National Urban League President speaks. January 20, 1994 (1:03:00)
      - Youth Services Department: "Shaping the Future, Creating a Vision", undated (Box-item 29.7)
        VHS, Footage taken at workshops and other events at a National Urban League Youth Conference, meant to provide youth with exposure to various cultures. (0:17:00)
      - Conference, 1991 (Box-item 29.8)
        VHS, Highlights from the 1991 National Urban League Conference on Making a Difference in the 1990's. (2:00:00)
      - Conference, 1993 (Box-item 29.9)
        U-matic, Annual Conference, Washington, D.C.
      - Conference, 1993 (Box-item 29.10)
        VHS, Keynote Speech from the 1993 Annual Conference, Washington, D.C. August, 1993 (0:25:00)
      - Conference, 1993 (Box-item 29.11)
        VHS, Footage from the 1993 National Urban League Conference. August, 1993 (0:30:00)
      - Conference, 1993 (Box-item 29.12)
        VHS, "Making the Transition," Civil rights challenges are discussed in the keynote speeches, Benjamin F. Chavis, Jr. August, 4, 1993 (0:50:00)
      - Conference, 1996 (Box-item 29.13)
        VHS, Keynote Speaker, Hugh B. Price. August 11, 1996 (0:53:00)
      - Conference, 1996 (Box-item 29.14)
        VHS, Introductions, Hugh B. Price, 6:00pm. August 11, 1996 (2:00:00)
      - Conference, 1996 (Box-item 29.15)
        VHS, Keynote Speaker Kweisi Mfume, "Political Action Now for the 21st Century Results." August 14, 1996 (0:39:00)
      - Conference, 2001 (Box-item 29.16)
        VHS, Reverend Kirbyjohn Caldwell, Family Session, relaxed. July 29, 2001 (2:40:00)
    - Award Recipients: Jaki Walker, Dr. Vivian Bull, 1995 (Box-item 29.17)
      U-matic, February, 1995
    - Award Recipients: Jaki Walker, Dr. Vivian Bull (Box-item 29.18)
    - Award Recipients: Jaki Walker, Dr. Vivian Bull, 1995 (Box-item 29.19)
      VHS, Jaki Walker remodels older homes for those with very low income; President of Linfield College increases minorities' communities and students' freedom of speech. February, 1995 (0:07:21)
    - Award Recipients: Jefferson Winners' Profile, 1991 (Box-item 29.20)
      VHS, (0:10:50)
    - Award Recipients: McCoy, Page, Prophet, undated (Box-item 29.21)
      VHS, News profiles. (0:26:24)
    - "Achievement Matters", 1988 (Box-item 29.22)
      VHS, Urban League of Portland, Sheds light on the positive achievements blacks have made. March 18, 1998 (0:15:46)
    - Automotive Training Centers' Partnership with Los Angeles Urban League, undated (Box-item 29.23)
      VHS, Overview of the Toyota Training Center. (0:12:57)
    - AAMCP: African American Male Connection Program, 1992 (Box-item 29.24)
      VHS, AAMCP talks about how African American males are portrayed in the media. (0:20:10)
    - Americorps Young Black History Committee: "I Have a Dream", undated (Box-item 29.25)
      VHS (0:23:46). Documentary created by ten local eighth graders about African American history in Portland. Danica Fierman ws project organizer for the Youth Black History Committee. Kim Moreland, Portland History Specialist, was narrator. Includes interview with community members Laura Jenkins and Susie Stokes.
    - Bingo with the Blazers, 1997 (Box-item 29.26)
      VHS, A bingo game with the Blazers and Seniors at the Urban League of Portland's Senior Center. October, 1997 (1:16:47)
    - Black Baccalaureate, 1998 (Box-item 29.27)
      VHS, Adult graduation ceremony, raw footage. (1:45:35)
    - Bridging the Communications Gap, undated (Box-item 29.28)
      VHS, An informational video about mushroom pickers and how the US Forest Service attempts to help them. (0:10:14 )
    - Bridging the Gap, undated (Box-item 29.29)
      VHS, Nike teaches students business skills and how to be positive and affective workers. (0:05:56)
    - Career Awareness Day, 1993 (Box-item 29.30)
      Betacam, PSA. November 2, 1993 (0:01:00)
    - Career Connections, 1996 (Box-item 29.31)
      VHS, KOIN-TV covers Career Connections event at the Urban League of Portland. (0:01:00)
    - Career Day, Reel to Reel, Edited. (Box-item 30.32)
    - Choice Not Chance, undated (Box-item 30.33)
      U-matic, African American Male Connection Program. (0:20:00)
    - City Scope: Urban League, undated (Box-item 30.34)
      VHS, Cityscope talks about the Urban League of Portland's Rainbow Center. (0:08:22)
    - Conference Day 1, 1994 (Box-item 30.35)
      VHS, Workshops from day 1 of the Urban League Conference. August 26, 1994(0:56:48)
    - Conference Day 2, 1994 (Box-item 30.36)
      VHS, Workshops from day 2 of the Urban League of Portland Conference. August 27, 1994 (1:13:13)
    - Conference, 1994 (Box-item 30.37)
      VHS, Highlights from the Urban League of Portland Conference. August 26, 1994 (1:51:25)
    - Careers in Caring, 1990 (Box-item 30.38)
      VHS, PSA for the family support center. August 30, 1990 (0:00:30)
    - Equal Opportunities Dinner, 1992 (Box-item 30.39)
      Reel to Reel, PSA, January 20, 1992 - February 11, 1992 (0:00:30)
    - Equal Opportunities Dinner, 1992 (Box-item 30.40)
      VHS, PSA, January 20, 1992 - February 11, 1992 (0:00:30)
    - Annual Dinner, 1992 (Box-item 30.41)
      DVD (1 of 2) duplicate of VHS recording of July 1992 Annual Dinner (item 43).
    - Annual Dinner, 1992 (Box-item 30.42)